<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gsoc2019 on Muhammad Usman</title>
    <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/tags/gsoc2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gsoc2019 on Muhammad Usman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 11:44:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://usmanmuhd.com/tags/gsoc2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code 2019: Improve Article Recommendation Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 11:44:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-final/</guid>
      <description>GSoC Project Proposal: Improve Article Recommendation Pipeline
Mentor: Bahodir Mansurov
Synopsis The project improved the article recommendation pipeline by solving the various issues in the article-recommender projects. The issues that were solved as a part of the project are:
 Remove duplicate Wikidata items from article recommendations Recommendation API translation endpoint stopped working Article recommendation API: replace WDQS with MW API morelike recommendation API: Bulk import data to MySQL in chunks  Links to code changes Merged:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Coding Period Update 4</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:40:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-7/</guid>
      <description>I started working on the 4th issue (Bulk import data to MySQL in chunks).
The flow of importing the tsv file to the database is:
 Generate the folder name, delete the folder if it exists and create a new one. Split the tsv file into chunks and place it in the folder. Insert the chunks one at a time. If the import fails at any given chunk then rollback the execution to a previous stable state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Second Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 18:40:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-6/</guid>
      <description>Second Evaluation Summary: Issue being worked upon:  T216750: Article recommendation API: replace WDQS with MW API  The WDQS dependency has finally been removed fully. The method being followed is:
 Get the langlinks and langlinkscount from props. Get ppprop if the page is diambiguation. Consider the wikidata item if it is not in the lang and is not disambiguation. Convert the data into required format for returning  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Coding Period Update 3</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:35:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-5/</guid>
      <description>I am working on the third issue. In the translation end point of the Recommendation API, currently we fetch the wikidata_id from the respective wikipedia API and then we have a SparQL query that gets the data about the sitelink_counts and removes the disambiguation pages.
I have pushed a patch to get all the data in a single request from the respective wikipedia API. This removes the dependency on Wikidata Query Service and ensures that the API responds faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC First Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:35:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-4/</guid>
      <description>First Evaluation Summary: Issues completed:  T216721: Remove duplicate Wikidata items from article recommendations T215222: Recommendation API translation endpoint stopped working  Issue currently being worked upon:  T216750: Article recommendation API: replace WDQS with MW API  Received the mentor evaluation. 🎉🎉
#eval1 { box-shadow: none; }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Coding Period Update 2</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:35:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-3/</guid>
      <description>I started working on the second issue. The Recommendation API translation endpoint used to fail intermittently. After investigating the issue, the point where the bug was being caused was found. The internal request being made to the MediaWiki API was returning a server error due to issues with the API (Russian MediaWiki API in our case). It was requesting 500 items at once. To overcome the issue I split the request being into batches of 50 at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Coding Period Update 1</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 18:51:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-2/</guid>
      <description>The coding period officially started from May 27. My first task was to Remove duplicate Wikidata items from article recommendations. I had a clear understanding of what had to be done to fix the issue. I sent in a patch after making the code changes. My mentor advised me to make a few changes which I fixed and the patch got merged.
During this time, I also attended the MediaWiki Training 2019 organized in Bangalore, India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC 2019 with Wikimedia Foundation</title>
      <link>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 20:24:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usmanmuhd.com/posts/gsoc-blog-1/</guid>
      <description>What is GSoC? Google Summer of Code is a program sponsored by Google to introduce students to open source programming. Students work on the projects mentored by different open source organizations. It is an incredible opportunity to learn the various tools and practices used in real world software.
My GSoC Selection Story I am a 3rd Year Computer Science Engineering student at PES University, Bangalore. I had known about GSoC since my 1st year in college, but could not participate as my college clashed with the GSoC coding period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
